DC Public Library Oral History Project OHP003
People's Archive, MLK Library
DC Public Library Oral History Project
1972-1992
People's Archive, MLK Library
District of Columbia. Public Library
OHP003
7.5 Linear feet
7 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts for most interviews. There is no transcript for 03-54. Series 2: Bound Editions Materials in this series consist of bound transcripts of two individuals, Nora Drew Gregory and G. R. F. Key. Additional copies of this series have been added to the Washingtoniana Book Collection. Series 3: Interviews Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for the following: 03-01, 03-02, 03-03, 03-05, 03-16, 03-17, 03-18, 03-19, 03-29, 03-30, 03-31, 03-39, 03-40, and 03-56.
Biographical / Historical
The DC Public Library was created by an act of Congress in 1896. The first branch of the DC Public Library was built in 1911 in Takoma Park. Soon after, additional facilities were added with a total of 26 branches across the District. In 1982, the DC Public Library established the Oral History Research Center (OHRC). The Center was funded in part by the D.C. Humanities Council. Since then, the Library has conducted its own oral histories as well as acquired tapes recordings and transcripts from individuals or groups who conducted their own oral histories to OHRC to enhance public access.
Custodial History
DC Public Library conducted these oral histories between 1972 and 1992. Deposit into the Library's collection occurred at the time the interview was conducted. The interviews were organized and conducted by Marcia M. Greenlee and Roxanna Deane.
Scope and Contents
Between 1972 and 1992 the DC Public Library conducted 29 oral history interviews with individuals who had a long association with and knowledge of Washington, D.C. Topics include childhood experiences, segregation, religion, neighborhoods, education, communities, employment, demographics and social life.
Oral History; Neighborhoods; Families; Religion; Segregation; Education
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for most interviews. There is no transcript for 03-54.
  - Helen Thompson, 1972 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Phillip Stone, 1972 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - George Stallings, 1980 September 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jane Barnes, 1980 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Benjamin Amos, 1983 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Louise Amos Singleton, 1983 February 15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Harold Lewis, 1983 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Viola Cotton, 1983 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Sidney C. Gray, 1983 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Edward L. Feggans, 1983 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Joseph Rappaport, 1983 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Frank Taylor, 1983 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Albert and Annie Long, 1983 October 12 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lola Louise Strange Johnson, 1983 October 18 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Marion Jackson, 1983 October 25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - J. Bernard Wyckoff, 1983 October 27 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Joseph L. Drew and Grace Ridgeley, 1983 December 7 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - James and Barbara Walker, 1983 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nora Drew Gregory, 1983 December 9 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Lucretia Blackstone, 1983 November 21 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Ruth Baer, 1992 February 19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Pearl Frager, 1992 March 7 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Alice J. Perry, 1992 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Helen Curling, 1992 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - J. George Frain (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Bound Editions
  Materials in this series consist of bound transcripts of two individuals, Nora Drew Gregory and G. R. F. Key. Additional copies of this series have been added to the Washingtoniana Book Collection.
  - Nora Drew Gregory, 1983 December 9 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Series 3: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master and patron access copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies of each audio cassette except for the following: 03-01, 03-02, 03-03, 03-05, 03-16, 03-17, 03-18, 03-19, 03-29, 03-30, 03-31, 03-39, 03-40, and 03-56.
  - Helen Thompson, 1972 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 03-01)
  - Helen Thompson, 1972 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 03-02)
  - Phillip Stone, 1972 February 1 (Box 4, Folder 03-03)
  - George Stallings, 1980 September 30 (Box 4, Folder 03-04)
  - Jane Barnes, 1980 November 18 (Box 4, Folder 03-05)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-06)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-07)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-08)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-09)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-10)
  - G. R. F. Key, 1982 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 03-11)
  - Benjamin Amos, 1983 January 18 (Box 4, Folder 03-12)
  - Benjamin Amos, 1983 January 18 (Box 4, Folder 03-13)
  - Louise Amos Singleton, 1983 February 15 (Box 4, Folder 03-14)
  - Louise Amos Singleton, 1983 February 15 (Box 4, Folder 03-15)
  - Harold Lewis, 1983 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 03-16)
  - Harold Lewis, 1983 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 03-17)
  - Harold Lewis, 1983 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 03-18)
  - Harold Lewis, 1983 May 11 (Box 4, Folder 03-19)
  - Viola Cotton, 1983 August 30 (Box 4, Folder 03-20)
  - Viola Cotton, 1983 August 30 (Box 5, Folder 03-21)
  - Viola Cotton, 1983 August 30 (Box 5, Folder 03-22)
  - Sidney C. Gray, 1983 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 03-23)
  - Sidney C. Gray, 1983 September 14 (Box 5, Folder 03-24)
  - Edward L. Feggans, 1983 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 03-25)
  - Edward L. Feggans, 1983 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 03-26)
  - Edward L. Feggans, 1983 September 19 (Box 5, Folder 03-27)
  - Joseph Rappaport, 1983 September 20 (Box 5, Folder 03-28)
  - Frank Taylor, 1983 September 29 (Box 5, Folder 03-29)
  - Frank Taylor, 1983 September 29 (Box 5, Folder 03-30)
  - Frank Taylor, 1983 September 29 (Box 5, Folder 03-31)
  - Albert and Annie Long, 1983 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 03-32)
  - Albert and Annie Long, 1983 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 03-33)
  - Albert and Annie Long, 1983 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 03-34)
  - Lola Louise Strange Johnson, 1983 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 03-35)
  - Lola Louise Strange Johnson, 1983 October 18 (Box 5, Folder 03-36)
  - Marion Jackson, 1983 October 25 (Box 5, Folder 03-37)
  - Marion Jackson, 1983 October 25 (Box 5, Folder 03-38)
  - J. Bernard Wyckoff, 1983 October 27 (Box 6, Folder 03-39)
  - J. Bernard Wyckoff, 1983 October 27 (Box 6, Folder 03-40)
  - Joseph L. Drew and Grace Ridgeley, 1983 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 03-41)
  - Joseph L. Drew and Grace Ridgeley, 1983 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 03-42)
  - Joseph L. Drew and Grace Ridgeley, 1983 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 03-43)
  - James and Barbara Walker, 1983 November 10 (Box 6, Folder 03-44)
  - James and Barbara Walker, 1983 November 10 (Box 6, Folder 03-45)
  - James and Barbara Walker, 1983 November 10 (Box 6, Folder 03-46)
  - James and Barbara Walker, 1983 November 10 (Box 6, Folder 03-47)
  - Nora Drew Gregory, 1983 December 9 (Box 6, Folder 03-48)
  - Nora Drew Gregory, 1983 December 9 (Box 6, Folder 03-49)
  - Lucretia Blackstone, 1983 November 21 (Box 6, Folder 03-50)
  - Lucretia Blackstone, 1983 November 21 (Box 6, Folder 03-51)
  - Lucretia Blackstone, 1983 November 21 (Box 6, Folder 03-52)
  - Ruth Baer, 1992 February 19 (Box 6, Folder 03-53)
  - Helen King (Box 6, Folder 03-54)
  - Pearl Frager, 1992 March 7 (Box 6, Folder 03-55)
  - Alice J. Perry, 1992 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 03-56)
  - Helen Curling, 1992 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 03-57)
  - Helen Curling, 1992 February 27 (Box 7, Folder 03-58)